[{"Year":"May2019","Questions":[{"Question":"What is the main function of book-keeping?","A":"communicating information","B":"interpreting information","C":"recording information","D":"summarising information","Answer":"C","Category":"Double entry book-keeping","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which does not reduce the owner’s capital?","A":"business expenses paid using a personal cheque","B":"cash withdrawn from the business bank account for personal use","C":"goods taken from inventory for personal use","D":"personal expenses paid using business cash","Answer":"A","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":""},{"Question":"What would be recorded by a debit entry in a ledger account?","A":"a decrease in an asset","B":"an increase in a liability","C":"an increase in an asset","D":"an increase in capital employed","Answer":"C","Category":"Double entry book-keeping","Guess":""},{"Question":"In April Meena sent Ralph invoices for $170, $240, $125 and a credit note for $63.  In the same month Ralph sent Meena a debit note for $70  and a cheque for $107. What was the balance on Meena’s account in Ralph’s books on 1 May?","A":"$295 credit","B":"$295 debit","C":"$365 credit","D":"$365 debit","Answer":"C","Category":"Double entry book-keeping","Guess":""},{"Question":"After receiving her bank statement Lyn updated her cash book. Which items would reduce the overdrawn balance in the cash book?, 1 bank interest received, 2 credit transfer received, 3 direct debit payment","A":"1 and 2 only","B":"1 and 3 only","C":"1, 2 and 3","D":"2 and 3 only","Answer":"A","Category":"Cashbook","Guess":""},{"Question":"After preparing a trial balance it was found that a cheque, $300, received from Oliver, had been debited in Oliver’s account and credited in the bank account. No other errors were found. Which statement about the trial balance before correcting the error is correct?","A":"The credit column was equal to the debit column.","B":"The credit column was $300 more than the debit column.","C":"The debit column was $300 more than the credit column.","D":"The debit column was $600 more than the credit column.","Answer":"A","Category":"Trial balance","Guess":""},{"Question":"A trader created a provision for doubtful debts. Why did he create this provision? 1 to ensure that money was available to cover bad debts, 2 to ensure that the current assets were not overstated, 3 to ensure that the matching /accruals principle was followed, 4 to ensure that the profit for the year was not overstated","A":"1 and 3","B":"1 only","C":"2 and 4 only","D":"2, 3 and 4","Answer":"D","Category":"Bad debts","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which item is revenue expenditure for a manufacturer?","A":"buying new office equipment","B":"extending the factory","C":"purchasing motor vehicles","D":"repairing machinery","Answer":"D","Category":"Revenue and capital expenditure","Guess":""},{"Question":"An item of revenue expenditure was treated as an item of capital expenditure. What was the effect of this error? Answer in the format: profit for the year, non-current assets","A":"overstated, overstated","B":"overstated, understated","C":"understated, overstated","D":"understated, understated","Answer":"A","Category":"Journal entries and correction of errors","Guess":""},{"Question":"What causes computer equipment to depreciate?","A":"depletion","B":"economic reasons","C":"passage of time","D":"physical deterioration","Answer":"B","Category":"Depreciation","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which items are used to calculate cost of goods sold?","A":"carriage on purchases, carriage on sales, net purchases, opening inventory","B":"carriage on purchases, closing inventory, net purchases, opening inventory","C":"carriage on sales, closing inventory, net purchases, opening inventory","D":"carriage on sales, closing inventory, net purchases, sales returns","Answer":"B","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"What is an advantage of trading as a partnership?","A":"A partnership is a separate legal entity.","B":"Decision-making is easy and quick.","C":"Liability is unlimited.","D":"Responsibilities are shared.","Answer":"D","Category":"Partnerships","Guess":""},{"Question":"A golf club sells refreshments to its members. Suppliers of refreshments were owed $250 on 1 January 2018 and $400 on 31 December 2018. Payments to suppliers during the year were $7200. The inventory at the end of the year was $100 less than the inventory at the start of the year. What was the cost of sales of refreshments for the year ended 31 December 2018?","A":"$7050","B":"$7150","C":"$7300","D":"$7450","Answer":"D","Category":"Other payables and other receivables","Guess":""},{"Question":"A business provided the following information. Sales 100 000, opening inventory 40 000, closing inventory 30 000, gross profit 5 000, What was the value of the purchases?","A":"$85 000","B":"$95 000","C":"$105 000","D":"$115 000","Answer":"A","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"What is not included in a statement of changes in equity of a limited company for the year ended 31 March 2019?","A":"an issue of additional ordinary shares that was made during the year","B":"an interim dividend paid to the ordinary shareholders on 1 November 2018","C":"a proposed final dividend which is to be paid to ordinary shareholders on 1 August 2019","D":"a transfer made to general reserve from retained earnings on 31 March 2019","Answer":"C","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"A business’s sales are $100 000, the expenses are $30 000 and the profit for the year is $20 000. What is the gross profit/sales ratio?","A":"10%","B":"50%","C":"70%","D":"80%","Answer":"B","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"A business prepares its accounts on the basis that it will continue to trade in the foreseeable future. Which accounting principle is being applied?","A":"accounting entity","B":"accounting year","C":"going concern","D":"matching/accruals","Answer":"C","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":""},{"Question":"A cheque paid by a business for fuel for the delivery vehicle was recorded in the books of the business. A cheque paid by the business owner for fuel for his motorcycle was not recorded in the books of the business. Which accounting principle was applied?","A":"accounting entity","B":"going concern","C":"materiality","D":"money measurement","Answer":"A","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which statement is not correct about reasons for using international accounting standards?","A":"helps when making comparisons between companies","B":"improves the reliability of accounting information","C":"narrows the areas of difference between companies","D":"makes the preparation of financial statements less time consuming","Answer":"D","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":""}]},{"Year":"Nov2018(11)","Questions":[{"Question":"Which statements about book-keeping and accounting are correct? Accounting is performed periodically rather than daily. Accounting relies on having accurate book-keeping records. Book-keeping includes the preparation of financial statements. Book-keeping involves the recording of financial transac","A":"1, 2 and 4","B":"1 and 3","C":"2, 3 and 4","D":"2 and 4","Answer":"A","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":""},{"Question":"A trader invested $4000 into the business. $2000 was used to pay a credit supplier. The rest of the money was paid into the business bank account. What changes would take place within the accounting equation?","A":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities –$2000 –$4000 +$2000","B":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities +$2000 +$2000 no effect","C":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities +$2000 +$4000 –$2000","D":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities +$4000 +$4000 no effect","Answer":"C","Category":"Journal entries and correction of errors","Guess":""},{"Question":"Wilma bought 55 items from Margot at a list price of $40 each, subject to a 15% trade discount. Wilma later returned 25 items as they were faulty. Which document did Margot issue to Wilma for the returned items?","A":"credit note for $850","B":"credit note for $1000","C":"debit note for $850","D":"debit note for $1000","Answer":"A","Category":"Business documents","Guess":""},{"Question":"The bank agreed to allow Dan an overdraft with a limit of $500. What did this mean?","A":"A sum of $500 would be transferred into Dan’s account by the bank.","B":"All cheques issued by Dan would be paid by the bank.","C":"Cheques issued by Dan would be paid by the bank provided the account was not overdrawn by more than $500.","D":"Only cheques issued by Dan for less than $500 would be paid by the bank if there was not enough money in the account.","Answer":"C","Category":"Bank reconciliation statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"On 30 September 2018, Ahmed’s bank statement showed a credit balance of $2500. Ahmed found that a cheque issued for $90 and a deposit of $500 had not been included on the bank statement. What was the balance at bank shown in Ahmed’s cash book on 30 September 2018?","A":"$1910","B":"$2090","C":"$2910","D":"$3090","Answer":"C","Category":"Bank reconciliation statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which statement about a debit balance brought down on a ledger account is not correct?","A":"It may represent a loss.","B":"It may represent a prepaid expense","C":"It may represent an accrued expense.","D":"It may represent an asset.","Answer":"C","Category":"Double entry book-keeping","Guess":""},{"Question":"On 1 September 2018 Chan owed Tan $570. During September 2018 the following transactions took place. Tan sold goods, $380, on credit to Chan Chan returned goods, $150, to Tan Chan paid Tan $500 by cheque What was the balance brought down on Chan’s account in Tan’s ledger on 1 October 2018?","A":"$300 credit","B":"$300 debit","C":"$840 credit","D":"$840 debit","Answer":"B","Category":"Double entry book-keeping","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which name is given to a statement of ledger balances on a particular date?","A":"bank reconciliation statement","B":"general ledger","C":"statement of financial position","D":"trial balance","Answer":"D","Category":"Trial balance","Guess":""},{"Question":"The balance of which account will appear in the debit column of a trial balance?","A":"carriage inwards","B":"discounts received","C":"provision for doubtful debts","D":"purchases returns","Answer":"A","Category":"Trial balance","Guess":""},{"Question":"Ella rents business premises. She owed rent at both the start and the end of the financial year. How can rent payable for the year be calculated?","A":"rent paid – amount owing at start of year","B":"rent paid – amount owing at start of year + amount owing at end of year","C":"rent paid + amount owing at end of year","D":"rent paid + amount owing at start of year – amount owing at end of year","Answer":"B","Category":"Other payables and other receivables","Guess":""},{"Question":"Bashir maintains a provision for doubtful debts of 3% of the trade receivables at the end of the year. On 31 August 2017 trade receivables amounted to $70 000. On 31 August 2018 trade receivables amounted to $73 000. Which double entry should Bashir make on 31 August 2018?","A":"debit $ credit $ income statement 90 provision for doubtful debts account 90","B":"debit $ credit $ income statement 2100 provision for doubtful debts account 2100","C":"debit $ credit $ provision for doubtful debts account 90 income statement 90","D":"debit $ credit $ provision for doubtful debts account 2100 income statement 2100","Answer":"A","Category":"Bad debts","Guess":""},{"Question":"Leroy has an engineering business. On 31 May he received an invoice from AB Machines showing the following: cost of replacement parts for machine cost of repairs to machine cost of machine cost of installation of machine Which costs are capital expenditure in Leroy’s books?","A":"machine, installation","B":"machine only","C":"replacement parts, machine","D":"replacement parts, repairs, installation","Answer":"A","Category":"Revenue and capital expenditure","Guess":""},{"Question":"Why is depreciation charged on a non-current asset?","A":"to accumulate a fund of money to replace the asset","B":"to charge the cost of using the asset against income","C":"to determine the market value of the asset","D":"to ensure that profits are not understated","Answer":"B","Category":"Depreciation","Guess":""},{"Question":"Chris purchased a machine costing $15 000 on 1 January 2016. He depreciates the machine using the diminishing (reducing) balance method at 20% per annum. Which journal entry did Chris make on 31 December 2017?","A":"debit $ credit $ income statement 2400 provision for depreciation of machinery 2400","B":"debit $ credit $ income statement 3000 provision for depreciation of machinery 3000","C":"debit $ credit $ provision for depreciation of machinery 2400 income statement 2400","D":"debit $ credit $ provision for depreciation of machinery 3000 income statement 3000","Answer":"A","Category":"Depreciation","Guess":""},{"Question":"Hossam took out a 5-year bank loan on 1 January 2018. All of the money borrowed was used to purchase a delivery van. Under which heading will these items be shown in Hossam’s statement of financial position on  31 March 2018?","A":"bank loan delivery van current liability current asset","B":"bank loan delivery van current liability non-current asset","C":"bank loan delivery van non-current liability current asset","D":"bank loan delivery van non-current liability non-current asset","Answer":"D","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"Beth provided the following information at 31 December 2017. capital 1 January 2017\t26 000 profit for the year\t3 600 drawings\t2 500 long-term loan\t8 000 Beth paid a personal cheque to the business on 30 December 2017 amounting to $5000. What was the capital employed on 31 December 2017?","A":"$24 100","B":"$32 100","C":"$35 100","D":"$40 100","Answer":"D","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which businesses do not prepare a trading account section of an income statement? furniture store, gym, newsagent, toy shop, window-cleaner.","A":"1 and 2","B":"2 and 5","C":"3 and 4","D":"3 and 5","Answer":"B","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"X and Y are sole traders. They decided to form a partnership. Which group contains only disadvantages of forming a partnership?","A":"disagreements may occur between the partners, profits are shared","B":"disagreements may occur between the partners, risks are shared","C":"losses are shared, responsibilities are shared","D":"profits are shared, risks are shared","Answer":"A","Category":"Partnerships","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which may be included in an income and expenditure account?","A":"bad debts","B":"opening balance on the bank account","C":"purchase of equipment","D":"subscriptions received for the following financial year","Answer":"A","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"At the end of the financial year a sports club owed rent for the clubhouse. Some members had paid their subscriptions in advance for the following year. How would these items be recorded in the club’s statement of financial position?","A":"rent owing subscriptions paid in advance current asset current asset","B":"rent owing subscriptions paid in advance current asset current liability","C":"rent owing subscriptions paid in advance current liability current asset","D":"rent owing subscriptions paid in advance current liability current liability","Answer":"D","Category":"Clubs and societies","Guess":""},{"Question":"A business provided the following information. opening inventory\t$8000, closing inventory\t$10 000, rate of turnover of inventory\t12 times, mark-up\t50%, What was the revenue?","A":"$54 000","B":"$108 000","C":"$162 000","D":"$180 000","Answer":"C","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which group contains only indirect costs?","A":"carriage inwards, factory rent, wages of factory supervisors","B":"carriage inwards, raw materials, wages of machine operators","C":"depreciation of machinery, factory rent, wages of factory supervisors","D":"depreciation of machinery, raw materials, wages of machine operators","Answer":"C","Category":"Revenue and capital expenditure","Guess":""},{"Question":"A manufacturing business provided the following information. prime cost\t250 000, factory overhead expenses\t50 000, office and selling expenses\t25 000, work-in-progress at 1 January\t1 500, work-in-progress at 31 December\t2 500, What was the production cost of goods completed?","A":"$249 000","B":"$299 000","C":"$301 000","D":"$324 000","Answer":"B","Category":"Manufacturing accounts","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which items are statutory deductions from an employee’s gross pay?","A":"donation to charity and club subscription","B":"donation to charity and social security contribution","C":"income tax and club subscription","D":"income tax and social security contribution","Answer":"D","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":""},{"Question":"Karim works 40 hours a week at a rate of $5 per hour and any overtime is paid at time and a half. He is paid monthly in arrears. He worked 12 hours, 16 hours and 18 hours overtime in May, June and July respectively. How much was Karim paid in June? (Assume 4 weeks in a month)","A":"$800","B":"$890","C":"$920","D":"$935","Answer":"B","Category":"Manufacturing accounts","Guess":""},{"Question":"What is included in the working capital ratio (current ratio), but not the quick ratio (acid test  ratio)?","A":"cash","B":"inventory","C":"other receivables","D":"trade payables","Answer":"B","Category":"Ratio Analysis and interpretation","Guess":""},{"Question":"Kim has been in business for many years and expects this will continue. She provided the following information. premises\t at cost\t50 000, at market value\t65 000, trade receivables\t at book value\t14 000, Trade receivables included a debt of $2000 which was unlikely to be paid. At which total value were these assets recorded in Kim’s statement of financial position?","A":"$62 000","B":"$64 000","C":"$77 000","D":"$79 000","Answer":"A","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"What is the purpose of international accounting standards?","A":"to allow users to rely on the information in financial statements being error-free","B":"to enable accountants to get work easily anywhere in the world","C":"to enable non-accountants to understand all the information in financial statements","D":"to make it easier to compare financial statements prepared in different countries","Answer":"D","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":""}]},{"Year":"Nov2018(12)","Questions":[{"Question":"Ava had $4000 in the bank. She paid a supplier $575 by cheque in full settlement of $600 owing. Which changes would take place within the accounting equation?","A":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities –$600 –$25 –$625","B":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities –$600 +$25 –$625","C":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities –$575 +$25 –$600","D":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities +$575 –$25 +$600","Answer":"C","Category":"Other payables and other receivables","Guess":""},{"Question":"Winston returned goods to Hanif. Which entries will Winston make in his ledgers?","A":"debit entry credit entry ledger account ledger account general Hanif purchases purchases returns","B":"debit entry credit entry ledger account ledger account general purchases returns purchases Hanif","C":"debit entry credit entry ledger account ledger account purchases Hanif general purchases returns","D":"debit entry credit entry ledger account ledger account purchases purchases returns general Hanif","Answer":"C","Category":"Double entry book-keeping","Guess":""},{"Question":"On 30 September 2018, Ahmed’s bank statement showed a credit balance of $2500. Ahmed found that a cheque issued for $90 and a deposit of $500 had not been included on the bank statement. What was the balance at bank shown in Ahmed’s cash book on 30 September 2018?","A":"$1910","B":"$2090","C":"$2910","D":"$3090","Answer":"C","Category":"Bank reconciliation statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"On 1 September 2018 Chan owed Tan $570. During September 2018 the following transactions took place. Tan sold goods, $380, on credit to Chan Chan returned goods, $150, to Tan Chan paid Tan $500 by cheque What was the balance brought down on Chan’s account in Tan’s ledger on 1 October 2018?","A":"$300 credit","B":"$300 debit","C":"$840 credit","D":"$840 debit","Answer":"B","Category":"Double entry book-keeping","Guess":""},{"Question":"Seema’s financial year ends on 30 September. She rents premises at a monthly rent of $2000. During the year ended 30 September 2018 she paid $26 000 rent. Which journal entry will Seema make on 30 September 2018 to transfer the rent to the income statement?","A":"debit $ credit $ income statement 24 000 rent 24000","B":"debit $ credit $ income statement 26 000 rent 26 000","C":"debit $ credit $ rent 24 000 income statement 24 000","D":"debit $ credit $ rent 26 000 income statement 26 000","Answer":"A","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"Bashir maintains a provision for doubtful debts of 3% of the trade receivables at the end of the year. On 31 August 2017 trade receivables amounted to $70 000. On 31 August 2018 trade receivables amounted to $73 000. Which double entry should Bashir make on 31 August 2018?","A":"debit $ credit $ income statement 90 provision for doubtful debts account 90","B":"debit $ credit $ income statement 2100 provision for doubtful debts account 2100","C":"debit $ credit $ provision for doubtful debts account 90 income statement 90","D":"debit $ credit $ provision for doubtful debts account 2100 income statement 2100","Answer":"A","Category":"Bad debts","Guess":""},{"Question":"Leroy has an engineering business. On 31 May he received an invoice from AB Machines showing the following: cost of replacement parts for machine cost of repairs to machine cost of machine cost of installation of machine Which costs are capital expenditure in Leroy’s books?","A":"machine, installation","B":"machine only","C":"replacement parts, machine","D":"replacement parts, repairs, installation","Answer":"A","Category":"Revenue and capital expenditure","Guess":""},{"Question":"Why is depreciation charged on a non-current asset?","A":"to accumulate a fund of money to replace the asset","B":"to charge the cost of using the asset against income","C":"to determine the market value of the asset","D":"to ensure that profits are not understated","Answer":"B","Category":"Depreciation","Guess":""},{"Question":"Sally bought a non-current asset. It was to be used for 10 years, after which it would have no scrap value. Sally used the straight-line method of depreciation. Which statements are correct?","A":"accumulated depreciation after five years annual depreciation charge equalled half of cost decreased each year","B":"accumulated depreciation after five years annual depreciation charge equalled half of cost was constant","C":"accumulated depreciation after five years annual depreciation charge was more than half of cost decreased each year","D":"accumulated depreciation after five years annual depreciation charge was more than half of cost was constant","Answer":"B","Category":"Depreciation","Guess":""},{"Question":"A draft income statement showed a gross profit of $12 200. It was later found that carriage on purchases, $260, and carriage on sales, $230, had both been included as expenses in the profit and loss section of the income statement. What was the corrected gross profit?","A":"$11 710","B":"$11 940","C":"$12 460","D":"$12 690","Answer":"B","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"Raj is both a customer of and a supplier to Balbir. Raj’s account in Balbir’s sales ledger showed a debit balance of $300. There was a credit balance of $100 on Raj’s account in the purchases ledger. A contra entry between the two accounts was agreed. Which entry would Balbir make in Raj’s account in the purchases ledger?","A":"credit $100","B":"credit $200","C":"debit $100","D":"debit $200","Answer":"C","Category":"Control accounts","Guess":""},{"Question":"Michael’s financial year ends on 31 August. On 30 August 2018 he purchased a motor  vehicle using a bank loan which is repayable on       30 August 2020. On 31 August 2018 Michael had a bank overdraft. In which sections of Michael’s statement of financial position on 31 August 2018 did these items appear?","A":"motor vehicle bank loan bank overdraft current asset current liability non-current liability","B":"motor vehicle bank loan bank overdraft current asset non-current liability current liability","C":"motor vehicle bank loan bank overdraft non-current asset current liability non-current liability","D":"motor vehicle bank loan bank overdraft non-current asset non-current liability current liability","Answer":"D","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which may be included in an income and expenditure account?","A":"bad debts","B":"opening balance on the bank account","C":"purchase of equipment","D":"subscriptions received for the following financial year","Answer":"A","Category":"Clubs and societies","Guess":""},{"Question":"A club’s financial year ends on 31 July. During the year ended 31 July 2018 the following subscriptions were received. subscriptions for the year ended 31 July 2017 50, subscriptions for the year ended 31 July 2018 3400, subscriptions for the year ending 31 July 2019 20, How much would  be  included  in  the  receipts  and  payments  account  for  the  year  ended  31 July 2018?","A":"$3400","B":"$3420","C":"$3450","D":"$3470","Answer":"D","Category":"Clubs and societies","Guess":""},{"Question":"A trader does not keep full accounting records. How can credit purchases for his first year of trading be calculated?","A":"cheques paid + discounts received + amount owing to suppliers at year end","B":"cheques paid + discounts received – amount owing to suppliers at year end","C":"cheques paid – discounts received + amount owing to suppliers at year end","D":"cheques paid – discounts received – amount owing to suppliers at year end","Answer":"A","Category":"Journal entries and correction of errors","Guess":""},{"Question":"A trader provided the following information. revenue\t100 000, cost of sales\t60 000, gross profit\t40 000, profit for the year\t20 000. What was the mark-up?","A":"20%","B":"33.33%","C":"40%","D":"66.67%","Answer":"D","Category":"Ratio Analysis and interpretation","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which statements about ordinary shares are correct? 1 If a company is wound up ordinary shares are repaid after debentures, 2 Ordinary shares are a non-current liability of the company, 3 The holders of ordinary shares are the owners of the company.","A":"1 and 3","B":"1 only","C":"2 and 3","D":"3 only","Answer":"A","Category":"Shares and capital","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which items are included in the equity section of the statement of financial position of a limited company?","A":"ordinary shares, retained earnings, debentures and current liabilities","B":"ordinary shares, retained earnings and debentures only","C":"ordinary shares and retained earnings only","D":"ordinary shares only","Answer":"C","Category":"Shares and capital","Guess":""},{"Question":"During the financial year, a manufacturing company’s payments included the following. purchase of a new machine running costs of the machine Where would these appear in the financial statements prepared at the end of the financial year?","A":"machine running costs of machine manufacturing account income statement","B":"machine running costs of machine manufacturing account manufacturing account","C":"machine running costs of machine statement of financial position income statement","D":"machine running costs of machine statement of financial position manufacturing account","Answer":"D","Category":"Manufacturing accounts","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which group contains only indirect costs?","A":"carriage inwards, factory rent, wages of factory supervisors","B":"carriage inwards, raw materials, wages of machine operators","C":"depreciation of machinery, factory rent, wages of factory supervisors","D":"depreciation of machinery, raw materials, wages of machine operators","Answer":"C","Category":"Manufacturing accounts","Guess":""},{"Question":"A factory employee records his time of arrival and departure each day. Which document is used for recording his hours of work?","A":"clock card","B":"payroll register","C":"time sheet","D":"wages sheet","Answer":"A","Category":"Manufacturing accounts","Guess":""},{"Question":"Which items are statutory deductions from an employee’s gross pay?","A":"donation to charity and club subscription","B":"donation to charity and social security contribution","C":"income tax and club subscription","D":"income tax and social security contribution","Answer":"D","Category":"Manufacturing accounts","Guess":""},{"Question":"A trader provided the following information. revenue\t95 000, purchases\t40 000, opening inventory\t20 000, closing inventory\t18 000, cost of sales\t42 000, What was the rate of turnover of inventory?","A":"2.10 times","B":"2.21 times","C":"5 times","D":"5.28 times","Answer":"B","Category":"Ratio Analysis and interpretation","Guess":""},{"Question":"A business provided the following information about its percentage of gross profit to sales. Year 1\t40%,  Year 2\t38%, Year 3\t35%, What could explain the changes in the percentage of gross profit to sales?","A":"Cost of sales is decreasing.","B":"Expenses are decreasing.","C":"Quantity of goods sold is decreasing.","D":"Selling price is decreasing.","Answer":"D","Category":"Ratio Analysis and interpretation","Guess":""},{"Question":"A business values its inventory at the lower of cost and net realisable value. Which accounting principle is being applied?","A":"accounting entity","B":"dual aspect","C":"money measurement","D":"prudence","Answer":"D","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":""},{"Question":"What is the purpose of international accounting standards?","A":"to allow users to rely on the information in financial statements being error-free","B":"to enable accountants to get work easily anywhere in the world","C":"to enable non-accountants to understand all the information in financial statements","D":"to make it easier to compare financial statements prepared in different countries","Answer":"D","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":""}]}]